Guide to the William Styron Papers, 1855-2019 and undated RL.01267
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Printed Material Series, 1900-2019 and undated
  - Serials Group
    - 1983, Jan., Moviegoer (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "Meryl Streep and Kevin Kline" by William Wolf (p. 9)
    - 1983, Apr., Commonwealth (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "Styron's Choice" by Lisa M. Antonelli (p. 39)
    - 1983, Dec., Esquire (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "The Short Classy Voyage of JFK" (p. 124)
    - 1984, Jan 6, Publishers Weekly (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      Quote from Styron about novel in progress (p. 60)
    - 1984, Sept.-Oct., Duke (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "Inside the Creative Mind" by Georgann Eubanks (p. 2)
    - 1984, Dec., Vanity Fair (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "In Celebration of Capote" (p. 120)
    - 1984, Summer, The Southern Review (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "I, Stingo: The Problem of Egotism in Sophie's Choice" by William Heath (p. 528)
    - 1986, Summer, Southern Coalition Report on Jail and Prisons (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
    - 1986, Fall, Tidings (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "Styron Reminisces about Boyhood on the James" (p. 6)
    - 1987, Mar.7, The Nation (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      A Symposium: "Cigarette Ads and the Press" (p. 283)
    - 1987, Aug., Esquire (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "A Tidewater Morning" (p. 85)
    - 1987, Winter, Southern Coalition Report on Jails and Prison (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
    - 1988, Nov. 11, L'Express (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "Styron: vive Jefferson" with Jacques Renard (p.8)
    - 1988, Fall/Winter, Colony News (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      Issue devoted to Styron's being awarded the MacDowell Medal
    - 1989, Dec., Vanity Fair (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "Darkness Visible" (p. 212)
    - 1989-1990,Fall/Winter, Martha's Vineyard (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "William Styron Speaks His Mind" with William Marks (p. 36)
    - 1989, Focus (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "William Styron Visits NCSU" by Jinnie Davis (p. 1)
    - 1990, Jan., North Carolina State (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "The Legacy Renewed" by Terri Leith (p. 7); "The Works of William Styron" by Terri Leith (p. 9)
    - 1990, Dec.-1991, Jan., Duke (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      Review of Darkness Visible: a Memoir of Madness by H. Keith H. Brodie, M.D. (p. 50); Excerpt from Darkness Visible (p. 51)
    - 1991, Mar. 21,Image (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "Through a Glass Darkly" by Mark Hertsgaard (p. 10)
    - 1993, Winter/Spring, Duke University Libraries (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      Address to the City Lights Society (p. 2)
    - 1995, Sept. 18, The New Yorker (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "A Case of the Great Pox" (p. 62)
    - 1995, Oct.8, The New York Times Magazine (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "A Horrid Little Racist" (p. 80)
    - 1995, Spring, Traces (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "I'll Have to Ask Indianapolis" (p. 4)
    - Excerpt from Lie Down in Darkness (p. 13) (Box PM 9)
      "Ordeal and Renewal. David Laurence Chambers, Hiram Haydn, and Lie Down in Darkness" by J. Kent Calder (p. 14)
    - Undated, Esquire (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      "William Styron" by Walt Sandulli and Paul Duke (p. 25)
    - 2019, Fall, The Paris Review (Box PM 9)
      "The Spiral," gift of James L. W. West III
  - Volumes Group
    - 1900 - The Southampton Insurrection, by William Sidney Drewry (Box PM 10)
      Styron's copy with his marginalia.
    - 1924 - Eneas Africanus, by Harry Stillwell Edwards (Box PM 10)
    - 1961 - John Hartwell Cocke of Bremo. Agriculture and Slavery in the Ante-bellum South, by M. Boyd Coyner, Jr. (Box PM 10)
    - 1965 - An Examination of the Psychological Validity of Characters in 'Lie Down in Darkness', by Helen Slaby Mills (Box PM 10)
    - 1972 - To Choose Being: The Function of Order and Disorder in William Styron's Fiction, by Ray Wilson Ownbey (Box PM 11)
    - unspecified (Box PM 11)
    - 1973 - Esquire. The Best of Forty Years (Box PM 11)
      "My Generation," p. 13.
    - 1974 - Idea and Technique in the Novels of William Styron, by Philip W. Leon (Box PM 11)
    - 1974 - The Novels of William Styron. An Existential Study, by S. Laxmana Murphy (Box PM 11)
    - 1976 - The Development of William Styron's Artistic Consciousness: A Study of the Relationship Between Life and Work, by Eva Bamberger Mills (Box PM 12)
    - 1977 - William Styron's Literary Career, by Valerie Meliotes Arms (Box PM 12)
    - 1979 - The Best American Short Stories 1979, ("Shadrach," p. 56) (Box PM 13)
    - 1985 - Conversations with William Styron, edited by James L. W. West III (Box PM 13)
      Proof.
    - 1987 - The Nightmare of History in William Styron's 'The Confessions of Nat Turner,' by Daniel Fabricant (Box PM 13)
  - Clippings Group
    - Pre-1950-1989, 18 folders (Box PM 14)
    - 1990-98, undated, 7 folders (Box PM 15)
    - Clippings in French (Box PM 15)
    - French articles, Cette paisible poussière (Box PM 15)
    - Foreign Languages other than French (Box PM 15)
    - Articles on Darkness Visible (Box PM 15)
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, 3 folders (Box PM 15)
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, 9 folders (Box PM 16)
    - Lie Down in Darkness, 2 folders (Box PM 17)
    - The Long March (Box PM 17)
    - Set This House on Fire, 2 folders (Box PM 17)
    - Sophie's Choice, 5 folders (Box PM 17)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Materials
    - 1942-1997, undated, 5 folders (Box PM 18)
- Audiovisual Material Series, 1963-1996
  The Audiovisual Material series includes interviews, documentaries, and photographs. The bulk of the video is Dr. Joel Foreman's 1982 documentary, "William Styron: A Portrait" -- DVD use copies are available for all the footage shot the finished the program. Audio resources include several discussions, with participants including Ossie Davis and James Baldwin, from the late 1960s centering on the debate caused by Styron's The Confessions of Nat Turner, a conversation with Styron and Thérèse de St. Phalle in Russia, in-depth oral history interviews with Styron by Dr. Robert K. Morris in 1973 and by Dr. James L. West in 1987, and a 20-cassette audiobook of Sophie's Choice. Photographs include images of the Styron family, of Styron at ceremonies and speaking engagements, of the filming of "Sophie's Choice," and of Christchurch School.
  - William Styron: A Portrait, by Joel Foreman, 1981-1989; 1
    - Tape 1, Foreman Videotape: Interview with Vera Elsinboss, Styron friend and pharmacist (on cassette: 'Test tape - Canfield's pharmacy') 1982, Apr. 27, 1982-04-27; 1
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV01, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0001)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0001)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0001)
    - Tape 2, Foreman Videotape: Interview with Bob Munson, Roxbury marketer (on cassette: 'Munsun's store') 1982, Apr. 28, 1982-04-28; 2
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV01, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0002)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0002)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0002)
    - Tape 3, Foreman Videotape: Interior shots of Munson food market; Exterior shots of Styron property on Racum Road (on cassette: 'Munson's cutaways; outside cutaways - Styron's house') 1982, Apr. 28, 1982-04-28; 3
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV01, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0003)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0003)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0003)
    - Tape 4, Foreman Videotape: Styron driving through Roxbury with monologue on his residency (on cassette 'Styron's house; Ride to Munson's with W. S.') 1982, Apr. 28, 1982-04-28; 4
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV01, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0004)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0004)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0004)
    - Tape 5, Foreman Videotape: Rose and Bill Styron cooking and planning a dinner party; Styron soaks Virginia ham and talks about his heritage; Styron playing with his dogs (on cassette: 'Styron's house; Kitchen sequence; 1:30') 1982, Apr. 28, 1982-04-28; 5
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV01, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0005)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0005)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0005, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Video-file RL01267-DVD-0005.mp4)
    - Tape 6, Foreman Videotape: Styron walks through Revolutionary War graveyard and talks; His reflections on death (on cassette: 'Ham cutaways; Dogs outside') 1982, Apr. 28, 1982-04-28; 6
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV01, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0006)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0006)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0006, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Video-file RL01267-DVD-0006.mp4)
    - Tape 7, Foreman Videotape: Styron completing his daily walk; Scenes from rural Roxbury (on cassette: 'Part II graveyard walk; 1st. take on pond/boat at end of tape') 1982, Apr. 28, 1982-04-28; 7
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV02, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0007)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0007)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0007)
    - Tape 8, Foreman Videotape: Styron reads selected passages from his work (on cassette: 'begin tape/pond/boat; end pond/boat') 1982, Apr. 28, 1982-04-28; 8
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV02, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0008)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0008)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0008)
    - Tape 9, Foreman Videotape: Styron reads selected passages from his work (on cassette: 'Rose interview') 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 9
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV02, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0009)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0009)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0009)
    - Tape 10, Foreman Videotape:Interview with Rose Styron, 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 10
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV02, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0010)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0010)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0010, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Video-file RL01267-DVD-0010.mp4)
    - Tape 11, Foreman Videotape: Interview with Rose Styron, 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 11
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV02, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0011)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0011)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0011, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Video-file RL01267-DVD-0011.mp4)
    - Tape 12, Foreman Videotape: Interview with Rose Styron (on cassette: End Rose Styron/ Poem) 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 12
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV02, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0012)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0012)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0012, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Video-file RL01267-DVD-0012.mp4)
    - Tape 13, Foreman Videotape: Styron walks through Canfield Pharmacy and chats with Vera Elsinboss; Styron scrubs and cuts hock from Virginia ham, 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 13
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV03, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0013)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0013)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0013)
    - Tape 14, Foreman Videotape: Styron boils ham; images from the Styron kitchen; Styron enacts his daily writing modus operandi (on cassette: 'Styron at his bar/desk') 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 14
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV03, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0014)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0014)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0014, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Video-file RL01267-DVD-0014)
    - Tape 15, Foreman Videotape: Styron writing; shots of Styron living room (on cassette: 'Inside and outside of Styron house') 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 15
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV03, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0015)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0015)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0015, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Video-file RL01267-DVD-0015.mp4)
    - Tape 16, Foreman Videotape: Interview with Styron (on cassette: 'Beauty shots bar room; Styron dining room interview') 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 16
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV03, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0016)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0016)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0016)
    - Tape 17, Foreman Videotape: Styron skins and slathers ham; additional shots of Styron writing as sun sets (on cassette: 'Ham glaze') 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 17
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV03, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0017)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0017)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0017)
    - Tape 18, Foreman Videotape: Styron reads and comments upon letters to his father (on cassette: 'Styron interview') 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 18
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV03, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0018)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0018)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0018)
    - Tape 19, Foreman Videotape: Styron interview, 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 19
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV04, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0019)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0019)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0019)
    - Tape 20, Foreman Videotape: Styron interview, 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 20
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV04, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0020)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0020)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0020)
    - Tape 21, Foreman Videotape: Styron interview, 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 21
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV04, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0021)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0021)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0021)
    - Tape 22, Foreman Videotape: Styron interview, 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 22
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV04, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0022)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0022)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0022)
    - Tape 23, Foreman Videotape: Styron reads from works, 1982, Apr. 29, 1982-04-29; 23
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV04, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0023)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0023)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0023)
    - Tape 24, Foreman Videotape: Styron drives through Roxbury / monologue on same (on cassette: hand cutaways / Bill driving) 1982, Apr. 30, 1982-04-30; 24
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV04, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0024)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0024)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0024)
    - Tape 25, Foreman Videotape: Same as # 24; shots of Roxbury; shots of Munson's farm (on cassette: Sheep farm) 1982, Apr. 30, 1982-04-30; 25
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV05, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0025)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0025)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0025)
    - Tape 26, Foreman Videotape: Styron walking on Roxbury backroads, no commentary, 1982, Apr. 30, 1982-04-30; 26
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV05, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0026)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0026)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0026)
    - Tape 27, Foreman Videotape: Shots of items in Styron parlor; shots of dinner, 1982, Apr. 30, 1982-04-30; 27
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV05, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0027)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0027)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0027)
    - Tape 28, Foreman Videotape: Styron cuts ham and talks about heritage; opening shots of Styron party 1982, Apr. 30, 1982-04-30; 28
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV05, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0028)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0028)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0028, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Video-file RL01267-DVD-0028.mp4)
    - Tape 29, Foreman Videotape: Shots of Styron and guests in living room; interview with John Marquand, 1982, Apr. 30, 1982-04-30; 29
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV05, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0029)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV08, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0029)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0029, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Video-file RL01267-DVD-0029.mp4)
    - Tape 30, Foreman Videotape: Styron's dinner party, 1982, Apr. 30, 1982-04-30; 30
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV05, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0030)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV09, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0030)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0030, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Video-file RL01267-DVD-0030.mp4)
    - Tape 31, Foreman Videotape: Shots of Styron dinner in dining room, 1982, Apr. 30, 1982-04-30; 31
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV06, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0031)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV09, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0031)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0031)
    - Tape 32, Foreman Videotape: Dinner in dining room; interview with Arthur Miller, 1982, Apr. 30, 1982-04-30; 32
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV06, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0032)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV09, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0032)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0032)
    - Tape 33, Foreman Videotape: Dessert and conversation, 1982, Apr. 30, 1982-04-30; 33
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV06, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0033)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV09, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0033)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0033)
    - Tape 34, Foreman Videotape: Interview with John Marquand (on cassette: John Phillips interview; Roxbury cutaways) 1982, Apr. 30- May 1, 1982-04-30; 1982-05-01; 34
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV06, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0034)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV09, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0034)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0034)
    - Tape 35, Foreman Videotape: Interior and exterior shots of Canfield Pharmacy; exterior shots of Styron house, 1982, May1, 1982-05-01; 35
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV06, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0035)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV09, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0035)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0035, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Video-file RL01267-DVD-0035.mp4)
    - Tape 36, Foreman Videotape: Styron interview, 1982, May1, 1982-05-01; 36
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV06, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0036)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV09, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0036)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0036)
    - Tape 37, Foreman Videotape: Styron interview (Roxbury cuts), 1982, May1, 1982-05-01; 37
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV07, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0037)
      - Digibeta videocassette preservation copy (Box AV09, Video-cassette RL01267-dbcam-0037)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV09, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0037)
    - Tape 38, Foreman Videotape: "William Styron: A Portrait," produced by Joel Foreman, 1982(Master Copy, "Second generation," 58:35), 38
      - 3/4-inch videocassette original (Box AV07, Video-cassette RL01267-UM-0038)
      - VHS videocassette use copy (Box AV07, Video-cassette RL01267-VHS-0001)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV11, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0039)
  - Other video materials, 1981-1989; 2
    - "William Styron," CBS Cable Signature, 1981, Dec. 14(VHS Use Copy, Approx. 20:00), 1981-12-14; 39
      - Betamax videocassette original (Box AV07, Video-cassette RL01267-BMX-0001)
      - VHS videocassette use copy (Box AV07, Video-cassette RL01267-VHS-0002)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV11, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0042)
    - "First Edition: William Styron," PBS interview,1986, 40
      - VHS videocassette original (Box AV07, Video-cassette RL01267-VHS-0003)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV11, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0040)
    - "The Vineyard Voice," Interview with Styron, Producer and Host William Marks, MA,1989,Summer, 41
      - VHS videocassette original (Box AV07, Video-cassette RL01267-VHS-0004)
      - DVD use copy (Box AV11, Video-disc RL01267-DVD-0041, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Video-file RL01267-DVD-0041.mp4)
  - Audio materials, 1963-1996; 3
    - William Styron reading from Lie Down in Darkness (Calliope Records, CAL-12 33 1/3 rpm long play 7-inch), 1963; 42
      - Phonodisc original (Box AV11, Audio-phonodisc RL01267-PD-0001)
      - Phonodisc original (Box AV11, Audio-phonodisc RL01267-PD-0002)
    - Wm. Styron on The Confessions of Nat Turner, programmed for (L.C. Phillips) "Literature at Large" on Nov. 29, 1967, Central State. (Recorded at Wilberforce University, Ohio, Nov. 21, 1967), 1967-11-21; 43
      - 1/4" open reel original (Box AV11, Audio-reel RL01267-RR-0001)
      - Compact disc preservation master (Box AV11, Audio-disc RL01267-CD-0001)
    - An informal discussion over lunch with Mr. William Styron, author of The Confessions of Nat Turner, on April 25, 1968. Held at Silliman College, Yale University, under the auspices of the Silliman College Hot Line Hot Lunch program, with 67 member of the College participating., 1968-04-25; 44
      - 1/4" open reel original (Box AV11, Audio-reel RL01267-RR-0005)
    - Ossie Davis, Bill Styron, James Baldwin on "Confessions of Nat Turner," May 1968 at Eugene's, Beverly Hills, 1968 May; 45
      - 1/4" open reel original (Box AV11, Audio-reel RL01267-RR-0003)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0040)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0081)
    - Wm. Styron, Ossie Davis, and Mike Wallace phone interview, from Wallace at Large, 8/1/68, 1968-08-01; 46
      - 1/4" open reel original (Box AV11, Audio-reel RL01267-RR-0004)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0041, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Audio-file RL01267-CS-0041_01.wav)